A few really useful operations in Python,
going back to my simple list of squares.
So that would be four nm in range of six.
And nm times nm.
So if we look at our squares, they're right here.
Python has a sum operation that will let me quickly sum up
the values of any numbers as a sequence.
All I have to do is call the sum built in and pass the list to it.
So sum squares.
There's also a built-in min, which gives you the minimum value,
and a built-in max.
So the biggest number, smallest number.
We can also use some of the other built-in operations.
We looked at sorted in introduction to Python,
so that will give us the sorted numbers.
They're already sorted in ascending order.
What if I wanted to get a copy of the list back sorted
in descending order?
Pass in an argument.
Does anyone remember what it is?
Send into reverse equals to us.
Clubs by reverse equals true.
That'll give me back a list that's sorted in reverse.
And just very quickly, one more list comprehension.
Let's say I had a, say I had a string here.
Lottery numbers string.
And it contained my lottery numbers.
Nowing everything we know now, how would we get the maximum value
in this list of strings that are numbers?
How would we get the maximum value?
What's the first thing that we would need?
What does max take?
The list?
A list.
And what do the items in the list have to be?
String numbers versus...
They have to be numbers.
So how do we get a list of numbers from the string?
How do we get a list of strings from the string?
Split.
And I'm just going to make this a little shorter.
I'm going to reassign my variable just so it's a little bit easier
to read when I reassign it to lottery numbers.
So I'm going to say lottery numbers dot split.
What is my delimit or to split?
comma.
And here I'm going to have to add a space, right?
OK.
Now I have a list of strings.
We know that max takes a list of integers.
How do I get my list of strings to be a list of integers?
OK.
Can you do a list of comprehension, right?
So we're going to loop over four num in lottery nums.
But we're going to call split right in here.
And we're going to split on the comma space delimit.
What do we want to take?
What action do we want to take on each string in this list?
Pass it to him.
Exactly, right.
Now we have a list of numbers.
And as we saw earlier, I mean, this is getting a little bit complicated.
You'll probably want to introduce this as a variable, right?
But as you're typing along in the rep, you can build on this.
So what does max take a list of numbers?
And now we have a list of numbers, right?
So I can just put max and open parenthesis and put a closing parenthesis around all
of that.
It'll pass it to max.
And that gives me the biggest number in my list.